<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Development on The Janus List</title>
    <link>https://www.j4nu5.com/categories/development/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Development on The Janus List</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 10 Oct 2020 19:03:13 +0200</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.j4nu5.com/categories/development/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>The Reliable Engineer</title>
      <link>https://www.j4nu5.com/posts/the-reliable-engineer/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 10 Oct 2020 19:03:13 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.j4nu5.com/posts/the-reliable-engineer/</guid>
      <description>What is Reliability? One of the lenses through which I view my job is as a service that I provide to my immediate manager. This is different from any additional obligations that I may have to my employer.
From this lens, I want to provide such a quality of service where my manager is able to assign a task to me, and forget about it.
The extent to which I can meet this bar, is reliability.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Pelican Setup</title>
      <link>https://www.j4nu5.com/posts/pelican-setup/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Aug 2017 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.j4nu5.com/posts/pelican-setup/</guid>
      <description>Install Pelican:
1  sudo -H pip install pelican Markdown typogrify   Install Pelican themes
1 2 3  git clone --recursive https://github.com/getpelican/pelican-themes sudo /usr/local/bin/pelican-themes --install pelican-themes/Flex sudo chmod 755 /usr/local/lib/python2.7/dist-packages/pelican/themes/Flex   Install Pelican plugins
1  git clone --recursive https://github.com/getpelican/pelican-plugins   Fetch blog sources
1 2 3 4  git clone git@github.com:j4nu5/j4nu5.github.io.git cd j4nu5.github.io.git git fetch git checkout source   Setup for development
1  mkdir cache output   Verify plugins root</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Implementing Service Oriented Architecture using Http is a horrible idea</title>
      <link>https://www.j4nu5.com/posts/soa-using-http-considered-harmful/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 16 Nov 2014 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.j4nu5.com/posts/soa-using-http-considered-harmful/</guid>
      <description>Service Oriented Architecture is a commonly used design pattern in distributed and enterprise applications. It involves the creation and use of independent services that work together to produce the desired result. The most important benefits, of course, are separation of concerns and the ability to scale each service independent of others, leading to a clean, modular design.
A common problem faced during the design of a SOA system is the choice of communication protocol.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Abstract Classes and Factory Design Pattern in Python</title>
      <link>https://www.j4nu5.com/posts/abstract-classes-and-factory-design-pattern-in-python/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 19 Dec 2013 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.j4nu5.com/posts/abstract-classes-and-factory-design-pattern-in-python/</guid>
      <description>Abstract Classes are one of the most useful and important concepts in Object Oriented Programming. I&amp;rsquo;ll attempt to illustrate their usefulness, and their usage in Python 2.7 with the following (seemingly contrived) example:
Let us say, you want/have to implement posting updates on Facebook using Python. Your code might look something like this:
1 2 3 4 5 6 7 8 9  # Attempt 0: Bad code. def facebook_share_init(*args, **kwargs): # Initialize OAuth with facebook # .</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
